<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>NitroIQ Blog</title>
        <link>https://nitroiq.io/blog</link>
        <description>NitroIQ Blog</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Maintaining your Backlog]]></title>
            <link>https://nitroiq.io/blog/maintaining-your-backlog</link>
            <guid>https://nitroiq.io/blog/maintaining-your-backlog</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Maintaining your Backlog]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="why-is-backlog-maintenance-important">Why is backlog maintenance important?<a href="https://nitroiq.io/blog/maintaining-your-backlog#why-is-backlog-maintenance-important" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Why is backlog maintenance important?" title="Direct link to Why is backlog maintenance important?">​</a></h2>
<p>Maintaining a backlog, frankly just sucks.</p>
<p>It's a tedious task that teams rarely enjoy doing, but left unattended, will almost certainly lead to a variety of negative effects. I've often witnessed in my career that diagnosing a team's (product + engineering) inability to deliver on time, requires me to look at the backlog <strong>first</strong>!</p>
<p>The purpose of regularly maintaining (or grooming) a backlog is to ensure that the backlog is always up-to-date and that the team is always working on the most important issues. This is especially important for teams that are working on multiple projects at once, as it can be difficult to keep track of all the issues that need to be addressed.</p>
<p>Failure to maintain a backlog is a common occurence I've witnessed in my career and the effects can manifest in a variety of ways. However, the most common effects are:</p>
<ul>
<li>The team is working on issues that are not the most important (lack of prioritization)</li>
<li>Product Management is unable to provide accurate estimates on when a feature will be delivered (lack of estimation) to customers and management.</li>
</ul>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="5-tips-to-a-healthy-backlog">5 Tips to a Healthy Backlog<a href="https://nitroiq.io/blog/maintaining-your-backlog#5-tips-to-a-healthy-backlog" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 5 Tips to a Healthy Backlog" title="Direct link to 5 Tips to a Healthy Backlog">​</a></h2>
<ol>
<li>
<p><strong>Keep your backlog CURRENT and RELEVANT</strong> - The backlog should be updated regularly to reflect the current state of the project. This includes adding new issues, removing completed issues, and updating the status of existing issues. <strong>This also means regularly pruning OLD issues</strong>. For example: if an issue has been sitting in the backlog for more than 3 months, it's likely that it's no longer relevant. If it is, it should be re-prioritized and re-estimated. (3 months is a good rule of thumb, but it depends on your team's velocity).</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Backlog Issues should be ordered by priority</strong> - The backlog should be ordered by priority, with the most important issues at the top. This allows the team to focus on the most important issues first, and ensures that they are always working on the most important issues. This also helps Product Management to provide accurate estimates on when a feature will be delivered to customers and management.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Estimate your Issues</strong> - This may be controversial for some, but I believe that <strong>every issue should be estimated in a backlog</strong>. Estimaes will help guide the team on ranking priority and will help provide better accuracy on delivery dates and resource allocation. <em>Frankly, I'm not sure how you can prioritize a backlog without estimates... and if you aren't prioritizing you're not going to be able to forecast delivery dates.</em></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Backlog Issues should have a clear Definition of Done</strong> - Garbage belongs in the bin, not the backlog. If issues are arriving in the backlog without a clear definition of Done or Acceptance Criteria that everyone understands, then they should be rejected. <em>Also, see point #3 above. If you don't have a clear definition of Done, how can you estimate?</em></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Categorize and Tag your Issues</strong> - Tags and Labels should be used to help categorize or group issues together. This will help Product Management and Engineering to quickly filter and find issues that are related. Categorized issue, for instance, can help with prioritization as engineers can knock-out multiple issues that are related, and in the same part of the codebase, at the same time.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://nitroiq.io/blog/maintaining-your-backlog#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>Maintaining your backlog is an important ritual step in the Agile process. Backlogs act as a living queue of work that the business has prioritized for the team to work on. Without proper grooming, the backlog can become stale and lose its value, leading to a variety of negative issues.</p>
<p>For those of you using NitroIQ, we've made it easy to maintain your backlog with our ability to auto-score your backlog, highlight issues that require further refinement and are "too old", and increased visibility into your backlog health with our <a href="https://nitroiq.io/docs/metrics/understanding-doom-score/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Backlog Doom Score</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>jira</category>
            <category>backlog maintenance</category>
            <category>agile</category>
            <category>how-to</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[On Issue Churn in Agile shops]]></title>
            <link>https://nitroiq.io/blog/address-issue-churn-in-agile</link>
            <guid>https://nitroiq.io/blog/address-issue-churn-in-agile</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[The Importance of Addressing Issue Churn in the SDLC]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="what-is-issue-churn">What is Issue Churn?<a href="https://nitroiq.io/blog/address-issue-churn-in-agile#what-is-issue-churn" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to What is Issue Churn?" title="Direct link to What is Issue Churn?">​</a></h2>
<p>In the context of Agile software development, issue churn is a metric that can be used to measure the efficiency of a team.</p>
<p><strong>Issue churn is a term used to describe the amount (issues or points) that have rolled over from one sprint to the next.</strong></p>
<p>It is a measure of the amount of work that has <strong>not</strong> been completed in a given sprint. The <em>higher</em> the churn count, the <em>less</em> efficient the team is.</p>
<p>It's also important to represent Issue Churn as a Rate... that is, the amount of stories that are rolled over from one sprint to the next compared to the total number of stories that were planned for the sprint. <em>This is a more accurate representation of the team's efficiency.</em></p>
<p align="center"><img src="https://nitroiq.io/assets/images/jira_issue_churn2-da86288df0039035d4e7ab63302f72ea.png" class="doc_image"></p>
<div class="theme-admonition theme-admonition-tip admonition_xJq3 alert alert--success"><div class="admonitionHeading_Gvgb"><span class="admonitionIcon_Rf37"><svg viewBox="0 0 12 16"><path fill-rule="evenodd" d="M6.5 0C3.48 0 1 2.19 1 5c0 .92.55 2.25 1 3 1.34 2.25 1.78 2.78 2 4v1h5v-1c.22-1.22.66-1.75 2-4 .45-.75 1-2.08 1-3 0-2.81-2.48-5-5.5-5zm3.64 7.48c-.25.44-.47.8-.67 1.11-.86 1.41-1.25 2.06-1.45 3.23-.02.05-.02.11-.02.17H5c0-.06 0-.13-.02-.17-.2-1.17-.59-1.83-1.45-3.23-.2-.31-.42-.67-.67-1.11C2.44 6.78 2 5.65 2 5c0-2.2 2.02-4 4.5-4 1.22 0 2.36.42 3.22 1.19C10.55 2.94 11 3.94 11 5c0 .66-.44 1.78-.86 2.48zM4 14h5c-.23 1.14-1.3 2-2.5 2s-2.27-.86-2.5-2z"></path></svg></span>tip</div><div class="admonitionContent_BuS1"><p><strong>Some Issue Churn is Ok</strong></p><p>It's important to note that some issue churn is ok. In fact, it's expected. The goal is to minimize churn as much as possible, but it's not always possible to eliminate it completely.</p></div></div>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="the-causes-of-churn">The Causes of Churn<a href="https://nitroiq.io/blog/address-issue-churn-in-agile#the-causes-of-churn" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to The Causes of Churn" title="Direct link to The Causes of Churn">​</a></h2>
<p>Churn is caused by a variety of factors, including, but not limited to poor:</p>
<ul>
<li>Planning</li>
<li>Communication</li>
<li>Estimation</li>
<li>Prioritization</li>
<li>Execution</li>
</ul>
<p>Exact causes of churn will vary from team to team, and almost always have a large human and communication component. From our own experiences in helping teams diagnose churn issues, we have found that the most effective way to address churn is to have open discussions between engineering and product. This allows both teams to understand the root cause of churn and work together to address it.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="steps-to-reduce-churn-or-why-you-clicked-into-this-article">Steps to Reduce Churn (or why you clicked into this article...)<a href="https://nitroiq.io/blog/address-issue-churn-in-agile#steps-to-reduce-churn-or-why-you-clicked-into-this-article" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Steps to Reduce Churn (or why you clicked into this article...)" title="Direct link to Steps to Reduce Churn (or why you clicked into this article...)">​</a></h2>
<p>Many, if not all, of these factors are interrelated. For example, poor planning can lead to poor communication, which can lead to poor estimation, which can lead to poor prioritization, which can lead to poor execution. The key is to identify the root cause of churn and address it accordingly as a team (engineering and product).</p>
<p>Reducing churn is a team effort and requires a combination of planning, communication, estimation, prioritization, and execution. The key is to identify the root cause of churn and address it accordingly. There is no silver bullet for reducing churn, but there are some best practices that can help. Here are some tips for reducing churn:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p><strong>Plan Ahead</strong>: Planning ahead can help reduce churn by ensuring that all team members are on the same page and have a clear understanding of what needs to be done. This can be done by creating a backlog of work and prioritizing it based on importance and urgency. It is also important to communicate with stakeholders and get their input on what needs to be done.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Communicate Effectively</strong>: Effective communication is essential for reducing churn. This can be done by having regular meetings with stakeholders and team members to discuss progress and identify any issues that need to be addressed. It is also important to communicate with stakeholders and get their input on what needs to be done.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Estimate Accurately</strong>: Accurate estimation is essential for reducing churn. This can be done by using historical data to estimate how long it will take to complete a task and then adding a buffer for unexpected delays. It is also important to communicate with stakeholders and get their input on what needs to be done.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Prioritize Work</strong>: Prioritizing work is essential for reducing churn. This can be done by creating a backlog of work and prioritizing it based on importance and urgency. It is also important to communicate with stakeholders and get their input on what needs to be done.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Execute Efficiently</strong>: Efficient execution is essential for reducing churn. This can be done by using tools like NitroIQ to identify issues that are causing churn and then taking action to address them. It is also important to communicate with stakeholders and get their input on what needs to be done.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Improve Processes</strong>: Improving processes is essential for reducing churn. This can be done by identifying areas for improvement and then taking action to address them. It is also important to communicate with stakeholders and get their input on what needs to be done.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Improve Team Morale</strong>: Improving team morale is essential for reducing churn. This can be done by recognizing team members for their hard work and providing them with opportunities to grow and develop. It is also important to communicate with stakeholders and get their input on what needs to be done.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="https://nitroiq.io/blog/address-issue-churn-in-agile#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>Churn can be simple to measure but difficult to address in Agile shops. It requires a team effort and a combination of planning, communication, estimation, prioritization, and execution. The key is to identify the root cause of churn and address it accordingly. There is no silver bullet for reducing churn, but there are some best practices that can help.</p>
<p><em>I recently wrote a documentation article on <a href="https://nitroiq.io/docs/how_to/diagnosing_issue_churn/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Diagnosing Issue Churn</a> for those using NitroIQ to better their Agile practice.</em></p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>jira</category>
            <category>issue churn</category>
            <category>agile</category>
            <category>how-to</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How to Diagnose Problems in JIRA]]></title>
            <link>https://nitroiq.io/blog/how-to-diagnose-problems-in-jira</link>
            <guid>https://nitroiq.io/blog/how-to-diagnose-problems-in-jira</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[How to use NitroIQ to diagnose problems in JIRA]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="new-docs-how-to-section">New Docs How-To Section<a href="https://nitroiq.io/blog/how-to-diagnose-problems-in-jira#new-docs-how-to-section" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to New Docs How-To Section" title="Direct link to New Docs How-To Section">​</a></h2>
<p>We recently added a new section to our online documentation called <a href="https://nitroiq.io/docs/category/how-to/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">How-To</a>. This section is designed to help you get the most out of NitroIQ by providing you with step-by-step instructions on how to use NitroIQ to diagnose and address common problems in Jira and developer performance.</p>
<p>The How-To section is broken down into distinct categories that mirror the functionality in the application. For example, if you are having issues with issue churn, you can navigate to the <a href="https://nitroiq.io/docs/how_to/diagnosing_issue_churn/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Diagnosing Issue Churn</a> page to learn how to use NitroIQ to diagnose and address issue churn.</p>
<p>Future plans are to have these How-To articles linked directly from the application itself, so that you can quickly access them when you need them in the context of the application page you are on.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>nitroiq</category>
            <category>jira</category>
            <category>issue churn</category>
            <category>backlog maintenance</category>
            <category>how-to</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Live on the Atlassian Marketplace]]></title>
            <link>https://nitroiq.io/blog/nitroiq-atlassian-marketplace</link>
            <guid>https://nitroiq.io/blog/nitroiq-atlassian-marketplace</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Launching NitroIQ on the Atlassian Marketplace]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="live-on-the-atlassian-marketplace">Live on the Atlassian Marketplace<a href="https://nitroiq.io/blog/nitroiq-atlassian-marketplace#live-on-the-atlassian-marketplace" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Live on the Atlassian Marketplace" title="Direct link to Live on the Atlassian Marketplace">​</a></h2>
<p align="center"><a href="https://marketplace.atlassian.com/apps/1232080?tab=overview&amp;hosting=cloud" target="_blank"><img src="https://nitroiq.io/assets/images/atlassian_marketplace-e07957b2e87b6ba71539a3fcd16f7bb1.png" class="doc_image"></a></p>
<p align="center"><a href="https://marketplace.atlassian.com/apps/1232080?tab=overview&amp;hosting=cloud">NitroIQ Marketplace Page &gt;</a></p>
<p>After several months of work, NitroIQ is generally available to the public on the <a href="https://marketplace.atlassian.com/apps/1232080?tab=overview&amp;hosting=cloud" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Atlassian Marketplace</a>. <em>(Visit the page for a gallery of images and a short video)</em></p>
<p>NitroIQ is the JIRA plugin I always wanted and never had the time to build. After leaving my last job, I finally had the opportunity to work on a tool that would unlock the data hidden behind the JIRA scrum boards. Managing teams at scale and trying to find out where the bottlenecks are, which sprints perform better than others (and why), and which team members perform better than others (and why) is a difficult prospect in JIRA, and the included reporting doesn't help at all in this regard.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="why-nitroiq">Why NitroIQ?<a href="https://nitroiq.io/blog/nitroiq-atlassian-marketplace#why-nitroiq" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Why NitroIQ?" title="Direct link to Why NitroIQ?">​</a></h2>
<p>JIRA data is locked behind a lot of API calls and individual issue changelogs. I needed a way to parse all of this data and distill it down in simple to use charts and tables that answered those pressing questions that allowed me to unblock and tune my teams and processes for maximum efficiency.</p>
<p>So what questions is NitroIQ seeking to answer?</p>
<p align="center"><img src="https://nitroiq.io/assets/images/jira_board_column_flow-0c9e97241a6cc65eb4db308ff2832c1c.png" class="doc_image"></p>
<ul>
<li>Where are my bottlenecks in process, statuses, teams, etc...?</li>
<li>Are issue bouncing back-and-forth between statuses and teams?</li>
<li>Are we spending most of our time as a company working on bugs and not innovating?</li>
<li>What percentage of issues is rolling over sprint-over-sprint?</li>
<li>What is the state of the backlog? Issue age and readiness to work on.</li>
<li>Which team members are performing the most consistently sprint-over-sprint?</li>
</ul>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="reception-so-far">Reception so Far<a href="https://nitroiq.io/blog/nitroiq-atlassian-marketplace#reception-so-far" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Reception so Far" title="Direct link to Reception so Far">​</a></h2>
<p>More important than what they're saying, is what they're <strong>doing</strong> with the app!</p>
<p>Our team has witnessed teams change their behavior in several ways, from heavily pruning/adressing backlog items that are &gt; 120 days old or issues that score badly with our algorithms, to engineering leads using the data we expose to have honest conversations on performance with team members and conversations with the business on engineering throughput and technical debt.</p>
<p>When I sit by CTOs and Product Managers using the application, I hear two things:</p>
<ol>
<li>"This explains what I've been seeing", and</li>
<li>"Wait. This is interesting"</li>
</ol>
<p>On the former, NitroIQ is proving/confirming what a lead always thought was occurring and couldn't explain why. On the latter, NitroIQ is exposing some hidden insights previously locked behind JIRAs data access.</p>
<p>Both of these reactions are exactly what anyone looking for product-market-fit is wanting to hear.</p>
<p align="center"><img src="https://nitroiq.io/assets/images/intro-63a8532ac41ff3c0f27f3b9abcdebf26.gif" class="doc_image"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="next-steps">Next Steps<a href="https://nitroiq.io/blog/nitroiq-atlassian-marketplace#next-steps" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Next Steps" title="Direct link to Next Steps">​</a></h2>
<p>NitroIQ is publicly available on the marketplace, free for the first 30 days.</p>
<p>New features are headed out every week as the team works on them, with Kanban board support coming in the next few months.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>nitroiq</category>
            <category>jira</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NitroIQ - Private Beta]]></title>
            <link>https://nitroiq.io/blog/nitroiq-private-beta</link>
            <guid>https://nitroiq.io/blog/nitroiq-private-beta</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Launching NitroIQ in an invite-only private Beta]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="what-is-nitroiq">What is NitroIQ?<a href="https://nitroiq.io/blog/nitroiq-private-beta#what-is-nitroiq" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to What is NitroIQ?" title="Direct link to What is NitroIQ?">​</a></h2>
<p align="center"><img src="https://nitroiq.io/assets/images/intro-fbdb23587a54c0979895484157c925e2.gif" class="doc_image"></p>
<p>NitroIQ is a JIRA plugin (<em>only available by invite-only currently</em>) that helps Agile teams improve performance through insights, scorecards, and metrics powered by machine learning.</p>
<p>It's purpose is two-fold:</p>
<ol>
<li>Answer basic questions that engineering leaders and teams need to know about their performance sprint-over-sprint.</li>
<li>Using machine learning and decades of combined experience, <strong>recommend ways to improve processes</strong>.</li>
</ol>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="nitroiq-is-in-private-beta">NitroIQ is in Private Beta<a href="https://nitroiq.io/blog/nitroiq-private-beta#nitroiq-is-in-private-beta" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to NitroIQ is in Private Beta" title="Direct link to NitroIQ is in Private Beta">​</a></h2>
<p>We've had NitroIQ installed with friendly software organizations for a few months now, and the feedback has helped a lot in mapping out our next steps.</p>
<p>Being in private beta has fed the team important information, we would not have otherwise had, such as:</p>
<ul>
<li>Product-Market fit. <em>Is this useful?</em></li>
<li>Price sensitivity. <em>What is this worth to you?</em></li>
<li>Roadmap feedback. <em>What would you like to see in the next version?</em></li>
</ul>
<p>Additionally, every shop seems to configure JIRA differently, so building a tool that seemlessly plugs into an existing configuration and <strong>does not require changes in JIRA</strong> was nice to have pulled off.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="but-really-what-are-people-saying">But Really, what are people saying?<a href="https://nitroiq.io/blog/nitroiq-private-beta#but-really-what-are-people-saying" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to But Really, what are people saying?" title="Direct link to But Really, what are people saying?">​</a></h2>
<p>More important than what they're saying, is what they're <strong>doing</strong> with the app!</p>
<p>Our team has witnessed teams change their behavior in several ways, from heavily pruning/adressing backlog items that are &gt; 120 days old or issues that score badly with our algorithms, to engineering leads using the data we expose to have honest conversations on performance with team members and conversations with the business on engineering throughput and technical debt.</p>
<p>No one wants a high <em>Doom Score</em>, right?</p>
<p align="center"><img src="https://nitroiq.io/assets/images/backlog_score-641e87aefa62023e943ff018e641a427.png" class="doc_image"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="why-nitroiq">Why NitroIQ?<a href="https://nitroiq.io/blog/nitroiq-private-beta#why-nitroiq" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Why NitroIQ?" title="Direct link to Why NitroIQ?">​</a></h2>
<p>It is a tool that I've always wanted in my hands as I built high-performing teams in an Agile shop. Similar tools do exist, but they seem to focus on vanity metrics, random charts without a purpose, and all share the same trait in that they're horribly expensive for the typical SMB shop to justify.</p>
<p><strong>What's more amazing is that the team has designed NitroIQ to run entirely in the browser.</strong></p>
<p>So... <strong>our hosting costs ar near-zero and no data leaves your JIRA instance!</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Cheap? <!-- -->✅</li>
<li>Secure? <!-- -->✅</li>
<li>Profit! <!-- -->💲</li>
</ul>
<p>Meanwhile the few competitors that exist have taken on millions in funding, price their product outside of the reach of most companies, and require consultants and training to get up and running.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="next-steps">Next Steps<a href="https://nitroiq.io/blog/nitroiq-private-beta#next-steps" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Next Steps" title="Direct link to Next Steps">​</a></h2>
<p>We're on track for publishing NitroIQ to the Atlassian Marketplace within a month. Current plan is to make it available as a 30-day free trial to all that sign up. <em>Hopefully I don't regret writing this part on this blog post and we stay on track for that.</em></p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>nitroiq</category>
            <category>private-beta</category>
            <category>jira</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>