<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>NitroIQ Blog</title>
        <link>https://nitroiq.io/blog</link>
        <description>NitroIQ Blog</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How to Diagnose Problems in JIRA]]></title>
            <link>https://nitroiq.io/blog/how-to-diagnose-problems-in-jira</link>
            <guid>https://nitroiq.io/blog/how-to-diagnose-problems-in-jira</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[How to use NitroIQ to diagnose problems in JIRA]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="new-docs-how-to-section">New Docs How-To Section<a href="#new-docs-how-to-section" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to New Docs How-To Section" title="Direct link to New Docs How-To Section">​</a></h2><p>We recently added a new section to our online documentation called <a href="https://docs.nitroiq.io/how_to/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">How-To</a>. This section is designed to help you get the most out of NitroIQ by providing you with step-by-step instructions on how to use NitroIQ to diagnose and address common problems in Jira and developer performance.</p><p>The How-To section is broken down into distinct categories that mirror the functionality in the application. For example, if you are having issues with issue churn, you can navigate to the <a href="https://docs.nitroiq.io/how_to/diagnosing_issue_churn/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Diagnosing Issue Churn</a> page to learn how to use NitroIQ to diagnose and address issue churn.</p><p>Future plans are to have these How-To articles linked directly from the application itself, so that you can quickly access them when you need them in the context of the application page you are on.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>nitroiq</category>
            <category>jira</category>
            <category>issue churn</category>
            <category>backlog maintenance</category>
            <category>how-to</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Live on the Atlassian Marketplace]]></title>
            <link>https://nitroiq.io/blog/nitroiq-atlassian-marketplace</link>
            <guid>https://nitroiq.io/blog/nitroiq-atlassian-marketplace</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Launching NitroIQ on the Atlassian Marketplace]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="live-on-the-atlassian-marketplace">Live on the Atlassian Marketplace<a href="#live-on-the-atlassian-marketplace" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Live on the Atlassian Marketplace" title="Direct link to Live on the Atlassian Marketplace">​</a></h2><p align="center"><a href="https://marketplace.atlassian.com/apps/1232080?tab=overview&amp;hosting=cloud" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img loading="lazy" src="/assets/images/atlassian_marketplace-e07957b2e87b6ba71539a3fcd16f7bb1.png" class="doc_image img_ev3q"></a></p><p align="center"><a href="https://marketplace.atlassian.com/apps/1232080?tab=overview&amp;hosting=cloud" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">NitroIQ Marketplace Page &gt;</a></p><p>After several months of work, NitroIQ is generally available to the public on the <a href="https://marketplace.atlassian.com/apps/1232080?tab=overview&amp;hosting=cloud" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Atlassian Marketplace</a>. <em>(Visit the page for a gallery of images and a short video)</em></p><p>NitroIQ is the JIRA plugin I always wanted and never had the time to build. After leaving my last job, I finally had the opportunity to work on a tool that would unlock the data hidden behind the JIRA scrum boards. Managing teams at scale and trying to find out where the bottlenecks are, which sprints perform better than others (and why), and which team members perform better than others (and why) is a difficult prospect in JIRA, and the included reporting doesn't help at all in this regard.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="why-nitroiq">Why NitroIQ?<a href="#why-nitroiq" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Why NitroIQ?" title="Direct link to Why NitroIQ?">​</a></h2><p>JIRA data is locked behind a lot of API calls and individual issue changelogs. I needed a way to parse all of this data and distill it down in simple to use charts and tables that answered those pressing questions that allowed me to unblock and tune my teams and processes for maximum efficiency.</p><p>So what questions is NitroIQ seeking to answer?</p><p align="center"><img loading="lazy" src="/assets/images/jira_board_column_flow-0c9e97241a6cc65eb4db308ff2832c1c.png" class="doc_image img_ev3q"></p><ul><li>Where are my bottlenecks in process, statuses, teams, etc...?</li><li>Are issue bouncing back-and-forth between statuses and teams?</li><li>Are we spending most of our time as a company working on bugs and not innovating?</li><li>What percentage of issues is rolling over sprint-over-sprint?</li><li>What is the state of the backlog? Issue age and readiness to work on.</li><li>Which team members are performing the most consistently sprint-over-sprint?</li></ul><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="reception-so-far">Reception so Far<a href="#reception-so-far" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Reception so Far" title="Direct link to Reception so Far">​</a></h2><p>More important than what they're saying, is what they're <strong>doing</strong> with the app!</p><p>Our team has witnessed teams change their behavior in several ways, from heavily pruning/adressing backlog items that are &gt; 120 days old or issues that score badly with our algorithms, to engineering leads using the data we expose to have honest conversations on performance with team members and conversations with the business on engineering throughput and technical debt.</p><p>When I sit by CTOs and Product Managers using the application, I hear two things:</p><ol><li>"This explains what I've been seeing", and</li><li>"Wait. This is interesting"</li></ol><p>On the former, NitroIQ is proving/confirming what a lead always thought was occurring and couldn't explain why. On the latter, NitroIQ is exposing some hidden insights previously locked behind JIRAs data access.</p><p>Both of these reactions are exactly what anyone looking for product-market-fit is wanting to hear.</p><p align="center"><img loading="lazy" src="/assets/images/intro-63a8532ac41ff3c0f27f3b9abcdebf26.gif" class="doc_image img_ev3q"></p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="next-steps">Next Steps<a href="#next-steps" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Next Steps" title="Direct link to Next Steps">​</a></h2><p>NitroIQ is publicly available on the marketplace, free for the first 30 days.</p><p>New features are headed out every week as the team works on them, with Kanban board support coming in the next few months.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>nitroiq</category>
            <category>jira</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NitroIQ - Private Beta]]></title>
            <link>https://nitroiq.io/blog/nitroiq-private-beta</link>
            <guid>https://nitroiq.io/blog/nitroiq-private-beta</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Launching NitroIQ in an invite-only private Beta]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="what-is-nitroiq">What is NitroIQ?<a href="#what-is-nitroiq" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to What is NitroIQ?" title="Direct link to What is NitroIQ?">​</a></h2><p align="center"><img loading="lazy" src="/assets/images/intro-fbdb23587a54c0979895484157c925e2.gif" class="doc_image img_ev3q"></p><p>NitroIQ is a JIRA plugin (<em>only available by invite-only currently</em>) that helps Agile teams improve performance through insights, scorecards, and metrics powered by machine learning. </p><p>It's purpose is two-fold: </p><ol><li>Answer basic questions that engineering leaders and teams need to know about their performance sprint-over-sprint.</li><li>Using machine learning and decades of combined experience, <strong>recommend ways to improve processes</strong>.</li></ol><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="nitroiq-is-in-private-beta">NitroIQ is in Private Beta<a href="#nitroiq-is-in-private-beta" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to NitroIQ is in Private Beta" title="Direct link to NitroIQ is in Private Beta">​</a></h2><p>We've had NitroIQ installed with friendly software organizations for a few months now, and the feedback has helped a lot in mapping out our next steps. </p><p>Being in private beta has fed the team important information, we would not have otherwise had, such as:</p><ul><li>Product-Market fit. <em>Is this useful?</em></li><li>Price sensitivity. <em>What is this worth to you?</em></li><li>Roadmap feedback. <em>What would you like to see in the next version?</em></li></ul><p>Additionally, every shop seems to configure JIRA differently, so building a tool that seemlessly plugs into an existing configuration and <strong>does not require changes in JIRA</strong> was nice to have pulled off.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="but-really-what-are-people-saying">But Really, what are people saying?<a href="#but-really-what-are-people-saying" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to But Really, what are people saying?" title="Direct link to But Really, what are people saying?">​</a></h2><p>More important than what they're saying, is what they're <strong>doing</strong> with the app!</p><p>Our team has witnessed teams change their behavior in several ways, from heavily pruning/adressing backlog items that are &gt; 120 days old or issues that score badly with our algorithms, to engineering leads using the data we expose to have honest conversations on performance with team members and conversations with the business on engineering throughput and technical debt.</p><p>No one wants a high <em>Doom Score</em>, right?</p><p align="center"><img loading="lazy" src="/assets/images/backlog_score-641e87aefa62023e943ff018e641a427.png" class="doc_image img_ev3q"></p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="why-nitroiq">Why NitroIQ?<a href="#why-nitroiq" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Why NitroIQ?" title="Direct link to Why NitroIQ?">​</a></h2><p>It is a tool that I've always wanted in my hands as I built high-performing teams in an Agile shop. Similar tools do exist, but they seem to focus on vanity metrics, random charts without a purpose, and all share the same trait in that they're horribly expensive for the typical SMB shop to justify. </p><p><strong>What's more amazing is that the team has designed NitroIQ to run entirely in the browser.</strong> </p><p>So... <strong>our hosting costs ar near-zero and no data leaves your JIRA instance!</strong></p><ul><li>Cheap? ✅</li><li>Secure? ✅</li><li>Profit! 💲</li></ul><p>Meanwhile the few competitors that exist have taken on millions in funding, price their product outside of the reach of most companies, and require consultants and training to get up and running. </p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="next-steps">Next Steps<a href="#next-steps" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Next Steps" title="Direct link to Next Steps">​</a></h2><p>We're on track for publishing NitroIQ to the Atlassian Marketplace within a month. Current plan is to make it available as a 30-day free trial to all that sign up. <em>Hopefully I don't regret writing this part on this blog post and we stay on track for that.</em></p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>nitroiq</category>
            <category>private-beta</category>
            <category>jira</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>